# Alexander **Papiez**

#### Contact

31 Ashfield Road Gosforth Newcastle Upon Tyne NE3 4XL

alex.papiez@gmail.com

Tel:07948373631

## **Key Skills**

- 7 Years laboratory experience
- · Tutoring experience
- Competent user of LaTeX typesetting software
- Knowledge of the Python programming language
- Experienced user of Microsoft Office packages
- Able to work well independently and in a group
- Excellent spelling and grammar
- Ability to work to a deadline/ under pressure
- Full U.K. Driving Licence and own a car

## **Profile**

My attention and eye for detail have allowed me to be successful in my research career. As a self sufficient individual I have shown initiative in promptly solving problems which have arisen. In early 2016 I was invited to the International Congress on Marine Corrosion and Fouling in Toulon, France; where I presented aspects of my work to attendees. During the course of my studies I have consistently developed my ability to communicate ideas in a clear and concise manner while maintaining an engaging connection with the audience. I believe this is key to building rapports and successful working relationships.

# **Employment**

#### 09/2013-05/2016 Lab Demonstrator

Northumbria University

Worked to support the safe operation of lab-practical classes for undergraduate students. My knowledge in the field and previous experience with the course content meant I was able to act as an effective mentor and role model to students, helping to support the learning experience provided by the lecturer.

#### 02/2015 - 05/2015 GCE A-Level Tutor (Chemistry)

Newcastle Upon Tyne

I provided one-to-one tutoring support to a student preparing to sit their chemistry A-Level exams. I developed a lesson plan for each session covering a specific topic to ensure that student was given the best opportunity to understand the content and succeed in the exams.

#### 06/2013 - 09/2013 Production operative / Packer

Quorn Foods, Stokesley

During the summer I worked as part of a team on the Quorn production line. Duties included packing and palletizing the product, quality control, cleaning and some work in clean production areas.

# **Education**

#### 09/2013-Present PhD in Physical Polymer Chemistry

Northumbria University

Supervisors:	Dr. Justin Perry and Dr. Leslie Dix
Funded by:	AkzoNobel/International Paint
Thesis title:	Investigating the Rate of Release of Ions Across Polymer Phases
Summary:	In order to develop competitive products in a sustainable manner, anti-fouling paint manufacturers must consider the kinetics of biocide release. By studying the diffusion rate or

the rational design of anti-fouling technologies may be found. *Publications:* **Papiez**, A.P. Perry, J.J.B Ferguson, J. Wright, A.C.

Diffusion of Biocides in Polymeric Matrices: A Tool for Rational Coating Design, Poster presented at the International Congress on Marine Corrosion and Fouling, Toulon France, 2016

biocides in relation to material properties, insights useful for

**Papiez**, A.P. Perry, J.J.B. Downs, R.A.*Design and Implementation of a 3D Printed Microwave Flow Cell*, Poster presented at the R.S.C. Organic division meeting, Bradford, U.K. 2015

#### 09/2009 - 06/2013 MChem Applied Chemistry

Northumbria University

Classification:	1st with honours
Awards:	Best Post-graduate final-year project, 2013
4th Year	Synthesis and Characterization of Amino Functionalized
Project:	Methacrylate Polymers
3rd Year Project:	Predicting Mass Spectra Using Density Functional Theory Calculations

#### 09/2007-07/2009 GCE A-Levels

Stokesley Sixth Form College

A2:	Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics
AS:	Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, French

09/2002-07/2007 **GCSEs** 

Stokesley Comprehensive School

10 at grade A\*-C including Maths, English and Science

### Interests

I am a capable programmer and enjoy the creative thinking involved in solving technical problems; in conjunction with amateur DIY, I enjoy producing software and hardware to tackle real world problems.

I am an avid reader - my favourite genre is historical non-fiction as I enjoy learning about the past and the lessons it holds for today's world. This spurs my interest in politics and current affairs, which I enjoy debating in great detail.

I love the operas of Gilbert and Sullivan, my favourites being The Mikado and Iolanthe. I am fascinated by the intricate combination of language and musical theatre which they employ to make clever satirical comments.

## References

Dr.Justin Perry,
Enterprise Fellow

Health and Life Sciences Northumbria University, Ellison Building,

Ellison Place,

Newcastle Upon Tyne,

NE1 8ST,

Phone: 0191 227 3554,

Email:justin.perry@northumbria.ac.uk

Dr. Leslie Dix,
Senior Lecturer.

Health and Life Sciences Northumbria University,

Ellison Building, Ellison Place,

Newcastle Upon Tyne,

NE1 8ST,

Phone: 0191 227 3510,

Email: les.dix@northumbria.ac.uk